《黑镜》
再次把注意力回归到呼吸上
Now, once more return your attention to the breath.
注意你的呼吸会自然延续
Notice how your breathing continues...
无需外力
all by itself.
你的思绪可能飘走
Your mind may wander.
任它走吧
Simply watch it go.
保持平静
Calmly.
(新单)
(滑动接单)
不要评判
And without judgment.
(滑动接单)
(是否确认)
(已接单)
(伦敦  2018年)
天呐  你好快
God, that was so fast.
我不知道你就停在这里
I didn't realize you'd be parked right here.
- 是啊  刚下了客  - 那我走运了
- Yeah, just dropped somebody off. - Oh, it's my lucky day then.
我去老街...你都知道了哈
I'm going to Old Street... Oh, you've got the details.
你在那里工作吗
So you work in that place?
抱歉  想事呢  我没听到
Sorry, miles away, I didn't catch that.
你在那里工作吗  你上车的地方
Is that where you work, where I picked you up?
在生活碎片吗  不
At Smithereen? No.
就是公事
Just visiting.
我倒希望我在那里工作
I mean, I wish I worked there.
他们的设施啊
The facilities they've got in there,
还有自己的水疗  简直了
they've got their own spa. It's madness.
比利·鲍尔就是有钱啊
That's Billy Bauer money for you.
不说了
Anyway.
(丹咖啡馆)
《碎片》
我女儿叫克莉丝汀
My daughter's name was Kristin
克莉丝
Krissie.
20岁  大学生
Twenty years old. She was at university.
她自杀了  自尽了
She killed herself, took her own life,
随你怎么说吧
whatever you wanna call it,
已经18个月了
18 months ago now.
而且很突然
And it was out of the blue.
她的一个室友打给的我
One of her flatmates called me.
他们在浴室里发现了她
They'd found her in the bathroom.
我好生她的气
And I'm furious with her!
我好气她  不告诉我
I'm so fucking angry with her for not telling me.
我以为我知道...
I thought I knew, I...
我不知道
I didn't know.
我们最后一次通话时  她还开开心心的
Last time I spoke, she was happy...
就那样  她了结了一切
and just like that, she ended everything.
我不知道她为什么要那么做
And I don't know why she did it.
我问过自己数百万遍了
I've asked myself why a million times.
是因为个男孩吗
Was it over some boy
还是因为课业  因为这世界  还是我
or her course or the state of the world or me?
是我做了什么吗
Was it something I did?
问题在我脑子里打转
Round and round in my head
但没有答案  什么都没有
but there's no answer, there's nothing.
她不能回答了  所以
She's not here to say, so...
这永远不会停下  这...
it's never gonna stop, this...
想知道的渴望
needing to know.
永远不会停下
It's never gonna stop.
这才叫令人紧张
Talk about nerve-racking.
那是我第一次发言
That was my first time speaking.
当着大家说  他们真不好取悦
I mean, in front of everyone. Tough crowd.
你说得很好
Oh, you did really well.
- 是吗  - 对
- Really? - Yeah.
但是第一次  这挺可怕的  是吧
First time, though, shit scary, isn't it?
老实说  我不知道
Well, to be honest, I don't know.
你...
Have you...
我来之后还没见过你分享  你是...
You haven't spoken while I've been here. I mean, is it...
我就是还没找到合适的时机
I just haven't found the right moment yet.
就是在等合适的时机
Waiting for the right moment.
好了
Anyway.
你想去喝点东西吗
Do you fancy a drink?
我明天还很多事呢
I've got a bit of a long day tomorrow.
来吧  明天可能就死了呢
Come on. Might die tomorrow.
开玩笑的
Joke.
天呐  天呐
Oh, God. Oh, my God.
天呐
Oh, my God.
我真需要那个
I needed that.
没事  不用了
It's okay. It's okay.
- 我想让你也爽到  - 待会儿的吧
- I wanna make you cum, too. - In a bit maybe.
- 就是需要喘口气  - 都好久没做了
- Just need a bit... bit of a breather. - It's been ages.
我都不记得上次是什么时候了
Can't even remember the last time.
- 抱歉  你介意我...  - 不不
- Sorry, do you mind if I...? - No, no, no.
我知道这玩意很丢人
I know these things are undignified.
大概四个月前
Went on a date
我跟手机软件上认识的男人去约会
about four months back with a guy off an app.
第一道菜吃到一半  我讲了克莉丝汀的事
Halfway through the starter, I tell him about Kristin.
他的反应好像我说我得了癌症似的
He reacted like I said I'd got cancer.
那就是她
That's her.
是她室友寄给我的  本来放在她房间里
Her flatmate sent that to me. It was in her room.
该死  好  稍等我一下
Shit. Okay, give me a minute.
我想进入克莉丝汀的人际圈账户
I'm trying to get into Kristin's Persona account.
我每天都尝试登陆  你可以猜错三次
I try logging in every day. It gives you three wrong guesses,
然后就要被封几小时
then locks you out for hours.
每次我想到个密码  就记在这里
Every time I think of a guess, I write it in here.
这周我在猜我们度过假的地方
This week I'm into places we went on holiday.
我是她妈妈  按说他们该给我
I'm her mum. You'd think they'd give me
我女儿账户的密码  但不行
the password to my own daughter's account, but, no.
违反他们的隐私政策
Violates their privacy policy.
如果你能证明自己是亲属  它们可以纪念账户
They'll memorialize it if you prove you're next of kin.
配上遗像  弄成黑白的
Makes it sort of sepia with a tribute photo,
但那样就会删除收件箱
but that deletes the inbox.
我就想看收件箱
I just want the inbox.
我不知道  想看看有没有理由  答案
I don't know, see if there's a reason, an answer.
我也不知道我想要什么  好吧
I don't know what I want. Okay.
好
Right.
(密码输入错误  还有一次尝试机会)
(密码无效  账户封锁24小时)
好吧
Okay.
还有明天呢
Well, there's tomorrow.
注意你的呼吸会自然延续
Notice how your breathing continues...
无需外力
all by itself.
你的思绪可能飘走
Your mind may wander.
任它走吧
Simply watch it go.
保持平静  不要评判
Calmly and without judgment.
(滑动接单)
(是否确认)
(已接单)
我这就过去
I'm on my way now.
嗯
Yeah.
飞旧金山的头等舱
My first-class check-in San Francisco
还有三小时才起飞
flight's not for another three hours,
应该还有时间
so there should be time.
嗯  我正要上车
Yeah, yeah, I'm hopping in the car now.
好  好  再见
Okay. Okay, bye.
去机场  是吗
Airport, yeah?
3号航站楼
Terminal Three.
- 你在那里工作吗  - 生活碎片  对
- Do you work in that place? - Smithereen? Yeah.
卫星导航显示前方有事故
The sat nav's showing an accident coming up.
介意我走它指示的另一条路吗
Do you mind if I follow an alternate route it's showing me?
其实比平时的路线要快
It's actually quicker than the normal way.
- 好  可以  - 虽然有点奇怪
- Yeah, that's fine. - Might be a bit twisty
但这玩意总是能说对
but this thing always seems to know what it's doing.
把这个戴上  戴上
Put this on. Put it on.
戴上
Put it on!
绕在手腕上  圈住你的手腕
Round your wrists. Loop it round your wrists.
- 你为什么...  - 闭嘴照做
- Why are you... - Just shut up and do it.
- 快点  拉紧  - 我在弄呢
- Come on. Pull it tight. - I'm trying. I'm trying.
用牙  用牙拉紧
Use your teeth. Pull it with your teeth!
- 什么...  - 闭嘴
- What... - Shut up!
只要你乖乖照做  就不会有事  好吗
Nothing's gonna happen to you if you just do what I say. Okay?
你没事的  只需要听话照做  别动
You're okay. Just do what I say. Stay there.
该死
Fucking...
是为了钱吗
Is this about money?
我虽然在生活碎片工作
I know I work for Smithereen
但那不代表我就有钱
but that doesn't mean I've got money!
不用...
Don't need to...
什么...你干什么  我就是个实习生
What... What are you doing, man? I'm just an intern.
- 你干什么  - 你说什么
- What are you doing? - What did you say?
- 你说什么  - 我就是个实习生
- What did you say? - I'm just an intern.
西装革履  行李箱
With a suit, the luggage, the...
公文包  你为什么去机场
suitcase? Why are you going to the airport?
是行头  那里面是温妮莎的衣服
It's outfits. Clothes are in there for Vanessa.
- 温妮莎是谁  - 温妮莎·兰普顿
- Who the fuck is Vanessa? - Vanessa Lampton.
她是生活碎片的一个高管
She's an exec at Smithereen.
她的造型师叫我去希思罗机场
Her stylist told me that I need to go to Heathrow.
她有一堆衣服  她要选一件
She's got a bunch of outfits and she's gotta pick one.
我就负责这个  我就是个实习生
That's my job, man. I'm just an intern.
那你为什么打扮成这样  那是套西装
So why are you dressed like that? That's a suit.
- 你穿着西装呢  - 这是我第一周
- You're wearing a fucking suit. - It's my first week.
该死
Oh, fuck!
该死  该死
Fuck! Fuck!
好吧
Okay.
- 该死  - 该死
- Fuck! - Fuck!
该死的现代公司  每个人都那么年轻
Modern fucking companies! Everyone looks so fucking young!
让外人怎么能
How is anybody looking in supposed to
看出来你们的级别高低啊
have a sense of the fucking hierarchy?!
天呐  你们半数从楼里走出来的人
Jesus Christ! Half of you cunts coming out of the building
都打扮得像休学的学生
are dressed like fucking gap-year students.
搞什么...
I mean, what...?
该死  小屁孩
Fuck! Children.
整个生活碎片大楼
The whole Smithereen building
就是一屋子小屁孩
is a box full of fucking children
动动手指  到处搞事
getting their fingers everywhere.
划这个划那个
Wiping your shit.
把你们的破软件推到所有人的手机里
Your fucking app shit up on everybody's phone.
不论你看哪里  大家都掉在手机里了
Everywhere you look, people are hooked on the things!
就像连续吸烟
It's like chain-smoking.
你挣了不少钱吧
Did you make a lot of cash out of that, did you?
你们也一样沉迷
And you lot are hooked on them as well.
每个从那栋楼里出来的人都...
Every single person that comes out of that building's going...
都没人抬头看了
People don't even look up anymore.
天空就算变紫了
The sky could turn fucking purple
你们一个月都发现不了
and you cunts wouldn't notice for a month.
你就没抬头看  看我把你带哪来了
You didn't look up and look where that got you,
就那样坐在车后面
sitting in the back like that.
实习生  你为什么不穿得像个实习生点
An intern. Why didn't you dress like a fucking intern?!
天呐
Jesus!
好吧  想办法  想想办法
All right, work with it, work with it. Work with...
该死
Fuck.
- 站住  - 别杀我
- Stop! Stop! - Don't kill me.
- 我开枪了  - 别
- I'll shoot you! - No, no!
别动
Don't move.
- 我需要呼吸  对不起  - 闭嘴
- I'm trying to breathe! I'm sorry. - Shut up.
- 对不起  我再不跑了  - 起来  走
- I'm sorry. I won't run again. - Get up, move.
- 我不跑了  - 走  闭嘴
- I won't run. I won't run. - Move. Shut up!
- 进去  进车里  - 求你
- Get in. Get in the car. - Please!
- 进车里  - 不要
- Get in the car. - No, no!
- 别让我...  - 进去
- Don't put me... - Get in!
- 我不能进去  - 进去
- Look, I can't go in there. - Get in, get in.
我不能进去  我幽闭恐惧
I can't go in there. I've got claustrophobia, man.
我幽闭恐惧  求你了
I'm claustrophobic. Please, please, please!
- 进去  - 别让我进去
- Get in. - Please don't put me in there.
进去  照我说的做
Just get in. Just do as I say.
- 别  - 别出声
- Please. - Stay fucking quiet.
- 好吗  - 不要
- All right? - Please, please, don't put...
不  我不能待在狭窄的空间里
No! I can't be in small places!
求你了
Please! Please!
- 我不能...  - 该死的
- I just can't be in small... - Oh, fucking hell.
救命  求你
Help! Please.
- 好吧  闭嘴  - 求你
- Okay. Shut up, shut up, shut up. - Please, please.
好吧
Okay, okay.
看着我
Look at me.
你可以坐在后座
You can sit in the back seat
只要你戴上这个  别动
if you put this on and you don't move.
- 好吗  - 我不动
- Okay? Okay? - I won't, I won't, I won't move.
- 好  - 我非得戴上吗
- Okay. - Do I have to put it on?
对
Yeah.
你不趴下我杀了你
I'll fucking kill you if you don't keep down.
该死的
Fucking hell.
好了  躺下
Okay. Lie down.
我要吐了
I'm gonna be sick.
闭嘴  你没事的
Be quiet. You're okay.
我要吐了  求你
I'm gonna... I'm gonna be sick, please.
- 趴下  - 求你  我要吐了
- Get down! - Please, I'm gonna be sick.
- 我要吐了  求你  - 趴下
- I'm gonna throw up. Please. - Get down!
这什么啊
What are these?
他们没有奶酪洋葱的
They didn't have cheese and onion.
老天爷啊
Fuck's sake.
- 我要吐了  - 天呐  趴下  不然我打死你
- I'm gonna throw up. - Oh, God! Fucking down or I'll shoot you!
- 你看到了吗  - 什么
- Did you see that? - See what?
那车里有东西
Something in that car.
好像是有人脑袋上罩了个袋子
It looked like someone with a bag on their head.
什么
What?
不  我们去看看吧
No, let's check it out.
给我趴下
Just get fucking down!
看  就前面那辆
Yeah, look, that one up ahead.
看到了吗  蓝色那辆
See it? The blue one?
- 我看不到后面有人  - 我敢肯定有的
- I can't see anyone in the back. - I'm sure there was.
该死
Oh, fuck.
好吧
Okay.
看  他走了
There you go. Off he goes.
那边什么都没有
There's fuck all down that way.
趴着
Stay down.
别动
Don't fucking move.
- 趴着  - 怎么回事
- Stay down. - What's happening?
你就趴着
Just stay down.
WL60HFX
Whiskey, Lima, six, zero, Hotel, Foxtrot, X-ray.
总控收到
Control, received.
- 他没下车  - 是啊  他会跑的
- He's not getting out. - No. He's gonna be a runner.
准备好了吗
You ready?
总控  正在追车  车牌...
Control, in pursuit of vehicle registration...
怎么回事  怎么...
What's happening? What's...
老天爷啊
Jesus fucking Christ.
天呐  该死
Oh, my God. Oh, fuck!
趴着
Stay down.
- 下车来  - 孩子们
- Out of the car! - Boys!
- 别过来  - 马上下车来
- Stay back! - Out of the car now!
- 下车  - 我有枪
- Out of the car! - I've got a gun!
- 救命  - 我会打死他的  我有枪
- Help! - I'll shoot him. I've got a gun.
我会一枪崩了他的
I'll shoot him in the face!
退后  退远点  退后
Get back! Move further back! Move back!
- 退后  - 回车上  把车退回去
- Get back. Back. - Get in the car! Move your car right back!
- 没错  把车退回去  - 0号情况
- That's it. Move your car back! - Status zero.
- 我崩了他  - 嫌疑人持械劫持人质
- I'll shoot him in the face! - Armed suspect. Hostage taken.
躲到车后  低下头  别管自行车了  过来
Get behind the car. Heads down. Leave the bikes. Over here.
我打死他
I'll fucking shoot him!
趴着  趴好了
Stay down. Stay down.
她都走了  你就别...
Since she left, you won't, please,
求你了  你要什么都行  别...
don't. Please, whatever you want, don't...
头低下  躲在车后  压低身体
Heads down, heads down, stay behind the car. Stay low.
我得想想
I need to think.
- 孩子们  回家吧  - 我的车还在那儿
- Lads, go home. - My bike's down there.
你们快回家  快走
Lads, go home! Go!
- 等等  什么  - 稍后再来拿车吧
- Wait. What? - We can get the bikes later.
呼叫SJ  其他巡警在途
Reference, Sierra Juliet, other patrols are en route.
SJ收到  他在干什么
Sierra Juliet, received. What's he doing?
我不知道  他就坐在那里
I don't know. He's just sitting there.
比利·鲍尔
Billy Bauer.
我要跟比利·鲍尔说话
I want to speak to Billy Bauer.
你老板
Your boss.
我知道他是谁  但我不认识他
I know who he is but I don't know him.
我只是个实习生  记得吗
I'm just an intern, remember?
- 我知道  - 他可能在美国
- I know, I know. - He's probably in America or...
我怎么会...我不认识比利·鲍尔
Look, how do I... I don't know Billy Bauer.
我知道  我知道你不认识他
I know, I know you don't know him,
但你肯定认识一些认识他的人
but you'll know someone who knows someone who knows him.
- 你们公司的人  - 我才在那里做了一周
- From your company. - I've only been there one week.
我都不知道大家的名字
I don't even know anyone's name.
好吧  那你认识的级别最高的人是谁
Okay, so who's the highest-ranking person that you do know?
汉娜
Hannah.
嗯  人力资源的汉娜·肯特
Yeah, Hannah Kent in HR.
我算是归她管
She's sort of in charge of me.
好的  人力资源的汉娜·肯特
Okay. Okay. Hannah Kent in HR.
- 你可以给她打电话吗  - 什么
- So can you phone her? - What?
- 你手机里有她的电话吗  - 有
- Have you got her number in your phone? - Uh, yeah. Yeah.
可以给我吗
So can I have it?
你的手机呢
Your phone, where's your phone?
在另一辆车里
It's in the other car.
总控535C...
Control 535C...
- 该死  - 更新进展
- Fucking hell. - Status update.
你记得...
Can you remember, um...
那个人力资源的汉娜的电话号码吗
The HR woman, Hannah, can you remember her number?
- 她号码是多少  - 我不知道
- What's her number? - Um, I don't know.
- 如果我知道我肯定会告诉你的  - 好
- I'd tell you, I'd totally tell you if I knew it. - Okay.
汉娜能在电话上认出你的声音吗
Would Hannah recognize your voice on the phone?
- 可能吧  - 好  那你打给接待处
- Yeah, probably, yeah. - Right, so you could call reception
或是前台什么的  找汉娜
or the front desk or whatever, ask for Hannah?
我不知道  我还没那么做过呢
I don't know. I've never had to do that yet.
- 没事  - 但我没有手机
- That's okay. - But I don't have my phone.
我有  我有
I've got one. I've got one.
别耍花招
Don't fucking try anything.
我不会的
I'm not gonna try anything.
接待处的号码是多少
What's the number for reception?
我不知道
I don't know.
- 我没那么做过  - 算了  我谷歌
- I've never had to do that. - Fuck it. I'll Google it.
你看到枪了吗
You see the gun?
嗯  自动枪
Yeah, automatic.
看上去像真的
Yeah, it looked real.
去那边
Over there, over there.
(卡洛首相将与欧盟在布鲁塞尔谈判)
(呼入电话)
伦敦生活碎片  今天可以帮您什么
Smithereen London, how can I help you today?
汉娜  可以给我接汉娜吗
Hannah? Hi, can I speak to Hannah, please?
汉娜·肯特  人力资源的
Hannah Kent? From HR?
- 正在为您接通  - 谢谢
- Putting you through. - Thank you.
等她接了
When she answers,
就说你在车里  有个持枪的男人
say you're in a car and there's a man with a gun,
他威胁要打死你
he's gonna shoot you
除非他能跟比利·鲍尔通上话  好吗
unless he speaks to Billy Bauer. Okay?
好
Okay.
这里是生活碎片的汉娜·肯特
This is Hannah Kent at Smithereen.
我现在不在桌边
I'm not at my desk right now.
请留言  我会回电
Leave a message and I'll get back to you,
如果事情紧急  请致电07700...
or if it's urgent, you can reach me on 07700...
- 要给她留言吗  - 闭嘴
- Should I talk to her voicemail? - Shut up.
号码是07700900866
That's 07700 900866.
07700900866
07700 900866.
- 给  - 谢谢
- There you go. - Thank you.
(来电)
- 喂  - 汉娜
- Hello? - Hannah?
肯特女士  我是杰登
Mrs. Kent, it's, uh, Jaden.
什么...你到机场了吗  你没找到温妮莎吗
What... What, are you at the airport? You've not found Vanessa?
不不  听着  我在一辆车里  有个男人
No, no, no, listen. I'm in a car with a man
他有枪  他要跟比利·鲍尔通话
and he's got a gun and he needs to speak to Billy Bauer.
喂  他要跟比利·鲍尔通话
Hello? He needs to speak to Billy Bauer.
谁要跟比利·鲍尔通话
Who needs to speak to Billy Bauer?
那男人  持枪的男人
The man does, the gunman.
好吧  杰登  我不懂你在说什么
Okay, Jaden, I don't know what you're talking about.
你慢点说  我不懂
Can you slow down? I don't understand what...
- 我...  - 听好了  我有枪
- Look, I'm... - Listen carefully. I've got a gun.
我抓了你的员工  我要打死他
I've got your employee. And I'm going to shoot him
除非你马上帮我接通比利·鲍尔的电话
unless you get me Billy Bauer on the phone right now.
我是认真的
I'm serious.
警察也来了  他们正看着我呢
The police are here. They're looking at me.
我困在这儿了  我有枪  时间不多了
I'm stuck here, I've got a fucking gun. There's not much time.
我本不想这样的
I didn't want to do it like this
但我需要马上跟比利·鲍尔通话
but I need to speak to Bauer now.
好吧
Okay.
这是开玩笑吗
Is this a joke?
- 不是  - 不是
- No. - No!
他好像刚拍了张照片
I think he just took a photo.
你收到了吗
Did you get that?
是的
Yes.
- 那是你们的杰登吧  - 对
- That's your guy Jaden, yeah? - Yes.
别伤害他
Don't hurt him.
如果你帮我接通比利·鲍尔的电话
If you get me Billy Bauer on the phone,
就没人会受伤
no one gets hurt.
我只想跟比利·鲍尔  通电话
I just wanna speak with Billy Bauer on... on the phone.
好  我不知道怎么联系比利
Okay, I don't know how to get to Billy.
但你可以想办法
But you can find out.
我尽量吧
I can try to.
你可以保持通话吗
Can you stay on the line?
马上
Now.
我不会挂的
I'm staying on the line.
你确定这不是恶作剧吗
You sure it's not a prank?
我也不能百分百确定
I can't be a hundred percent,
如果这是耍人玩的  我可不想打去美国
but I don't wanna call the US if this is bullshit.
那边还是一大早呢
It's still bloody morning over there.
天呐
Oh, God.
(呼叫  佩内洛普·吴)
(加州  洛斯盖多斯)
玛丽姆  这对你来说也够早了
Maryam, this is early even for you.
我去
Holy shit.
好吧
Okay.
让唐和西奈尔10点去会议室见我
Have Don and Shonelle meet me in the boardroom in ten.
厉害的来了
Here comes the hotstepper.
- 拉警戒线  - 走吧  孩子们
- Get a cordon going. - Come on, lads.
看到人质了吗
Did you get a look at the hostage yet?
嗯  摘掉头套了  在后座
Yeah. Hood's off, he's in the back.
看他样子也就20出头
Early twenties, by the looks of him.
这是谈判专家大卫·吉尔克斯
This is David Gilkes, negotiator.
你们有谁跟嫌疑人说过话吗
Either of you speak to the suspect?
就他掏枪时说了一两句
For like a second when he pulled the gun.
他看上去像是醉酒或嗑药了吗
He seem pissed up? On something?
不  就是很生气
No, just angry.
我们平和一下气氛吧
Let's cut back on the razzmatazz.
情况是挺紧张  但最好别再搞出
I know it's tense but we're not risking a shit storm
斯特顿可怜的老发令枪先生那样的丑闻
like the whole Stretton thing with poor old Mr. Starter Pistol.
- 长官  - 我知道  但他根本没武器
- Ma'am, I... - Yes, I know but he was unarmed
而且那才过去不到一个月  大家还没忘呢
and it was less than a month ago. Memories aren't that short yet.
所以除非别无选择
So no critical shot
不要开致命枪
unless there's absolutely no choice.
- 好吗  - 是  长官
- Okay? - Ma'am.
你的鞋带开了
Your lace is undone.
长官  他们已查到了车辆
Ma'am, they've ID'd the car.
注册在埃莉诺·凯瑟琳·吉尔海尼名下
It's registered to an Eleanor Kathleen Gillhaney,
67岁  登记地址在伊维尔姆
sixty-seven years old, listed under an address in Ewelme.
- 那离这里就几英里吧  - 对
- That's, what, couple of miles from here? - Yeah.
- 我知道那里  - 好  你俩去敲门
- I know Ewelme. - Okay, you two go and give it a knock.
- 看她是否还好  - 是  长官
- See if she's okay. - Yes, ma'am.
长官  我让这些车退开
Ma'am, I'm gonna get these cars out of the way.
好
Right.
佩内  我们得告诉比利发生了什么
Pen, we have to tell Billy what's happening.
如果这事以枪战收尾
If this thing ends in some kinda of a shoot-out,
他至少该知道情况
he should at least be aware of the situation.
- 有发现  - 他可能会开始提更多要求
- Got a hit. - He could start making other demands.
- 稍等  唐  怎么了  - 他用的手机
- One moment, Don. What is it? - Okay, the cell he's calling from,
我到处查了  有匹配
I ran it through everything and got a match.
是登记在
It's registered
这个账户下的两步验证号码
as a two-step verification number on this account.
(克里斯·吉)
调出我们能查到的他的一切
Pull out whatever we can get on this guy.
他还在线上吧
He's still on hold, right?
让他听播放列表呢
Got him listening to a playlist.
比利·鲍尔
Billy Bauer.
他不会为我付赎金的
You know, he's not gonna pay a ransom on me.
他都不知道我是谁
He doesn't even know who I am.
他们确定是恐怖袭击了吗
Do they know if it's a terror thing yet?
还没人知道情况
No one knows anything.
你们还是回家吧
You should just go home.
- 时间线都爆炸了  - 我看看
- Timeline's going nuts. - Let's see.
- 总控  黑人人质  - 长官
- Control, IC3 hostage... - Ma'am.
我们知道人质身份了  生活碎片的员工
We know who the hostage is. He's from Smithereen.
那个什么社交公司
The social whatever company?
对  他们联系了伦敦警察厅
Yeah. They contacted the Met
说他们的一位实习生被持械劫持
to say one of their interns is being held at gunpoint.
杰登·汤明斯  枪手还发了照片
Jaden Tommins. The gunman sent a photo.
该死
Shit.
他是被派去办事的
He'd been sent on an errand.
他们用手机软件搭车客叫了辆车
They booked a cab through the Hitcher app.
他现在可不在出租车里
He's not in a cab now.
联系搭车客  查询司机信息
Call Hitcher, get what we can on the driver.
- 我们知道发照片的号码吗  - 知道
- We got the number that sent that photo? - Yep.
让情报部查下通话数据
Run the call data through intel.
他对他们说什么了
What did he say to them?
- 他说名字了吗  - 没有
- Did he give a name? - No name.
他什么都不肯说
He wouldn't tell them anything
但他说他要跟比利·鲍尔通电话
but he did say he needs to speak to Billy Bauer on the phone.
就那个比利·鲍尔吗
Billy Bauer as in Billy Bauer?
- 喂  - 我在
- Hello. - I'm here.
我是生活碎片的佩内洛普·吴
This is Penelope Wu from Smithereen.
我知道你要求跟鲍尔先生通话
I understand you've asked to speak with Mr. Bauer.
对  你们接通比利·鲍尔了吗
That's right. So have you got Billy Bauer on the line?
- 喂  - 抱歉  是的
- Hello? - Sorry. Uh, yes.
我们已经在尽全力了
We're doing everything we can.
我可以跟杰登说话吗
May I speak to Jaden?
- 他没事  - 我想确认他没事
- He's fine. - I just need to check he's okay.
- 告诉他们你没事  - 我没事
- Tell them you're okay. - Uh, I'm okay.
听到了吧  你们最好赶紧让比利·鲍尔听电话
There. So you'd better hurry up and get Billy Bauer on the phone.
他所在的地方时间还早
It's still very early where he is.
- 我们联系不上他  - 那我不管
- We're having difficulty reaching him. - That's not my problem.
那现在  你可以大致说下这是为了什么吗
Well, meantime could you maybe outline what this is regarding?
不  我只跟他说话
No. I'm only speaking to him.
好  但...
Sure, it's just...
我是首席运营官
I'm actually the COO.
好吧  那又如何
Okay. And?
这样或许更快  如果我能告诉他...
Well, it might be quicker if I can present him with a...
马上接通比利·鲍尔的电话
Just fucking get Billy Bauer on the phone right now.
我可不是开玩笑的
I'm not fucking around here.
我会崩掉他的脑袋的
I will blow his fucking head off!
- 你明白吗  - 抱歉  当然  我道歉
- Do you understand? - I'm sorry, of course, I apologize.
我会让你继续待机
I'm gonna put you back on hold.
我保证  我们在想办法了
I promise you we are working on it.
别太久了
Don't be long!
他状态可不稳定
Well, he's not stable.
怎么说啊  唐
In what way, Don?
老天爷啊
Jesus Christ.
我觉得那音乐对他没什么帮助
I don't think that music helped him any.
但我切换了线路  这样他在听歌时
But I switched the line so now while he's hearing that,
我们可以听到他那边的情况
we can listen in to see what's happening at his end.
就他妈糊弄我
Fucking messing me around.
这是我最后一天
This is my last day.
This is my last day. This is my last day.
这是我最后一天
这是我最后一天  这是我最后一天
This is my last day. This is my last day. This is my last day.
他在说什么
What's he saying?
这是我最后一天
This is my last day. This is my last day.
埃莉诺  吉尔海尼太太
Eleanor? Mrs. Gillhaney?
警察
Police.
有人吗
Hello?
有人吗  埃莉诺
Hello? Eleanor?
埃莉诺  你还好吗
Eleanor, are you okay?
吉尔海尼太太
Mrs. Gillhaney?
(鲍尔大获成功)
这里好像没人
I don't think anyone's home.
(半个世界都在使用生活碎片)
- 这是个怪胎  - 纳杰
- Got a weird one here. - Naj.
该死  就是他
Fucking hell, that's him.
真是疯狂  看啊
All right, this is mad, look.
这可好
Great.
一切都好吗
Everything all right?
嗯  我们在找埃莉诺·吉尔海尼
Yeah, we're looking for an Eleanor Gillhaney.
来晚了
Bit late.
她三月份死了
She, uh, died in March.
好  各位  等待指示
Okay, guys, stand by for instruction.
那是她儿子
That's her son.
克里斯  克里斯托弗  她死后他就搬了进来
Chris, Christopher. He moved in when she died.
也就几个月
Well, couple of months at any rate.
- 自己住吗  - 他独来独往的
- On his own? - Yeah, keeps to himself.
每天早上开车去上班  好像是在伦敦工作
Drives to work each morning, think he works somewhere in London.
他出什么事了吗
Has something happened to him?
已确认嫌疑人身份  克里斯托弗·吉尔海尼
Got a positive ID on the suspect. Name's Christopher Gillhaney.
好的
Okay.
他似乎住在过世母亲的家里
He seems to be staying at his late mum's place.
一堆欠付账单  房子也要被收回了
Lots of red bills, and it's up for repossession.
嫌疑人情况呢
What have you got on the suspect?
原是教师
Former teacher.
- 抱歉  他是个教师  - 曾经是  教IT的
- Sorry? He's a teacher? - Well, he was a teacher. IT.
他已被登记为失业两年了
He's been registered unemployed going on two years.
- 案底呢  - 查了所有记录  清清白白
- How's his record? - Fully DBS checked, he's squeaky clean.
唯一的结果是作为受害者
Only place he shows up is as a victim
2015年11月的一起交通事故
in a road traffic accident, November 2015.
酒驾司机撞到了他
Drunk driver plowed right into him.
包括酒驾司机在内  两人死亡
Two dead, including the drunk.
- 好  干得漂亮  纳杰玛  - 长官
- Okay, good work, Najma. - Ma'am.
老师会有真枪
Teacher with a real gun?
不是没有可能  但也不大可能
Not impossible, but not likely.
长官  联调局找你
Ma'am, it's the FBI.
- 什么  - 联调局  紧急电话
- What? - It's the FBI. Urgent call.
我是格蕾丝总警司
Chief Superintendent Grace.
你好  总警司
Hi, Chief Superintendent.
我是联调局的厄内斯托·克鲁兹
This is Ernesto Cruz from the FBI.
好的  抱歉  请问你有什么事
Right. Sorry, what's this regarding?
我们正在和硅谷的生活碎片联系
We're liaising with Smithereen, Silicon Valley.
他们也在电话上
They're also on this call.
什么  他们也在电话上
What, they're on the line as well?
是的  你好  我是生活碎片的佩内洛普·吴
Yes, hi, this is Penelope Wu from Smithereen.
和我在一起的还有法务部的唐和分析部的西奈尔
With me is Don from legal and Shonelle from analytics.
我是谈判专家大卫·吉尔克斯
David Gilkes, negotiator.
听着  吴女士  我们已经查明了嫌疑人的身份
Listen, Ms. Wu, we've identified the suspect.
克里斯托弗·迈克尔·吉尔海尼  之前是名教师
Christopher Michael Gillhaney, former schoolteacher,
33岁  他在生活碎片有档案
thirty-three years old. He has a Smithereen profile.
- 好  - 首先  克里斯托弗的电话在待机
- Right. - So first off, Christopher's on hold
但我们可以听到他的声音
but we are able to listen in to his end of the line
所以我们都能听到通话内容
so we'll share live feed of that with you guys.
好  很有用
Yeah. That's useful.
另外  我们可以提供他在本公司留下的信息
In addition, we figure we could share the data we have on him
以协助你们那边的谈判
to assist negotiations at your end,
但或许你们可以先告诉我们
but first, perhaps you could share with us
你们怎么看待他的行为
your perception of what he's doing.
可能是想勒索
Probably extortion,
至于是不是针对贵公司  这我们...
whether it's targeted at your company is something we don't...
绝对是针对我们
It's targeted.
- 你说什么  - 我们正在调查克里斯托弗
- Sorry? - We're looking into who Christopher is.
我们把他归为高智商  低收入人群
Group-wise we'd slot him into high intellect, low income.
通常都很愤怒
Often angry people.
对  我们查了他是否
Right, well, we checked to see if he'd ever
曾对生活碎片整体表示过敌意
expressed hostile sentiments towards Smithereen as an entity
但他的社交媒体中并无此表现
but nothing shows up on his social.
事实上  他的社交媒体已经空白一阵了
In fact, there's been nothing there at all for some time.
他的账户毫无活动
His whole account is dormant.
我不明白这有什么关联
I don't see how this is relevant.
但之后我们问了搭车客那边的人
But then we checked in with the Hitcher guys.
- 好  - 他接走杰登的那辆出租车
- Right. - So the cab that picked Jaden up
是登记在奥马尔·马西姆巴鲁名下
is registered to an Omar Masimbalu.
我觉得你也会认同
And a name like that, I think you'll agree,
这并不是吉尔海尼先生的真名
does not exactly match Mr. Gillhaney.
- 对  - 原来这是个被泄露的账户
- No. - Turns out it was a compromised account.
被人们在暗网上出售
People trade them on the dark web.
克里斯应该是通过那种方式获得了这个账户
Seems likely Chris got a hold of it that way.
你明白我的意思吗
You appreciate what I'm saying?
他一直在掩盖自己的行踪
He's been covering his tracks.
于是我们请求搭车客告知我们他的账户情况
So we asked Hitcher to share his account activity
看上去几周以来
and it seems for weeks,
他都只接
he'd been only accepting jobs
伦敦生活碎片外的乘客
specifically outside the Smithereen London address.
每天都停在公司外等着
Just parked up each day waiting
直到他接到一位这间公司的员工
until he got a job from someone inside the building.
他已计划良久
This... This is a whole plan he's had going on here.
这是一种专业的犯罪行为
I mean, this is sophisticated criminal behavior.
很难相信他之前没有犯过罪
I find it hard to believe he's never raised red flags before.
他完全没有案底
His record's totally clean.
他之前曾是受害者...
I mean, he was the victim in...
2015年的车祸
The auto accident in 2015.
他在这场车祸中失去了未婚妻  你知道吗
He lost his fiancée in that crash. Were you aware of that?
(酒驾受害人两个月后不治身亡)
不知道
No.
但你知道
But you are.
他在自己的主页上发过贴
There were historical posts inside his network,
吊唁  纪念
condolences, memorials,
事实上  克里斯就是那时脱离社交媒体的
and that's when Chris disengages, in fact,
不再和朋友联系  虽然他表现出了悲伤
not interacting with friends even though he's expressing grief.
你已经做足了功课
You've done your homework.
好了  我觉得这不是为了钱
Okay, I'm thinking this isn't about money.
- 大卫  - 请讲
- David. - Go on.
克里斯和鲍尔年纪相仿  对吗
Chris is about the same age as Bauer, right?
他们都有极客背景  对电脑很熟悉
They've both got geeky backgrounds, computers.
- 大卫  - 或许连克里斯自己都觉得是为了钱
- David. - Maybe even Chris thinks it's about money
但其实是为了地位
but it's actually about status.
鲍尔有钱  有权  受人尊敬
Bauer's got money, power, respect.
但克里斯托弗有什么
What's Christopher got?
他是个穷光蛋  开着出租车
He's skint. He's driving a hookie cab.
他失去了未婚妻  还有妈妈
He's just lost his fiancée, his mum as well.
要是克里斯托弗觉得他想要鲍尔所拥有的一切呢
What if Christopher thinks he wants what Bauer's got?
但他真正的目的只是引起他的注意
But really, it's just about getting his attention.
如果是这样呢
What if that's what's going on?
这能帮你说服他下车来吗
Is that gonna help you talk him out of that car?
如果他肯听我说  能
If he'll listen to me, yeah.
克里斯托弗
Christopher!
喂  克里斯托弗
Hello, Christopher?
克里斯托弗  我叫大卫·吉尔克斯
Christopher, my name is David Gilkes.
我是大卫  好吗
I'm David, okay?
如果你能看见的话  我就是那个在挥手的傻子
If you can see me, I'm the berk waving his arm in the air, okay?
穿着廉价西装的那个
The one in the cheap suit.
听着  这里有很多警察
Listen, there's a whole load of police here
老实说  他们只是在做自己的本职工作
and to be honest, they're just doing their jobs
但我觉得他们担心
but I think they're worried
你会伤到自己或其他人
you're gonna hurt yourself or someone else.
我觉得你不会这么做的  克里斯托弗
I don't think you will, Christopher,
但我不确定他们会不会这么想
but I'm not sure that they think that.
你知道他们什么样
You know how they get.
克里斯  是我打来的  克里斯
Chris, that's me calling you, Chris.
别烦我
Oh, leave me alone.
我只想跟你聊聊
I just wanna talk to you for a moment.
哈里斯  如果需要  你能一枪击中吗
Harris, if we need you, you got a clear shot?
现在还不能  人质就在枪手正后方
No clear shot yet. Hostage is directly behind the gunman.
你能闭嘴吗
Can you shut up, please?
快  把那个递给我
Quick. Can you hand me that?
克里斯  我知道你现在压力很大
Chris, I know you're pretty stressed at the moment.
- 你是谈判专家吗  - 我叫大卫
- Are you the negotiator? - My name is David...
谢谢了  大卫  你是谈判专家吗
Thanks for that, David. Are you the negotiator?
有人这么叫我  但我只是...
Well, some people call me that, but really I'm just a...
我读过谈判专家的报道
I've read up about negotiators.
你会假装是我的朋友
You'll pretend to be my friend
然后会慢慢尝试劝我投降
and then you'll slowly try to convince me to give myself up.
克里斯  你显然是个聪明人
Chris, you're obviously a smart guy
我就不废话...
so I won't bullsh...
如果平和的说服没用
And if gentle persuasion doesn't work,
你就会打电话分散我的注意力
you'll keep me distracted on the phone
直到你们的狙击手能一枪爆我头
long enough for one of your snipers to get a good head shot.
是这样吗  大卫
Is that right, David?
听着  咱们别...
Well, look, let's just try to...
不  你滚吧
No, no, let's just you fuck off.
赶紧挂断  我在等比利·鲍尔的电话
Get off the line. I'm waiting for Billy Bauer.
你就是那个穿廉价西装的人  对吧
Okay, you're the guy in the cheap suit, yeah?
- 你是这么说的  - 对
- That's what you said? - Yeah.
好  接下来这么办
Okay, so here's what's gonna happen.
我会数到一百
I'm gonna count to a hundred.
- 克里斯  - 好  那我数到五十
- Chris. - Okay. I'm gonna count to 50.
如果我没看到你上车  马上滚蛋
And if I don't see you get in your car and fuck off right away,
我就把他崩了
I'll blow his fucking head off!
- 克里斯  没必要这样  - 一  二...
- Chris, we don't need to do like that. - One, two...
哈里斯  能一枪命中吗
Harris, have you got a shot?
- 不  如果我开枪  - 四
- No, if I shoot, - ...four,
- 他们都得死  - 五
- I'll kill them both. - five...
- 六  七  八  九  - 他在虚张声势
- ...six, seven, eight, nine... - He's bluffing.
大卫  我们不能冒险  你清楚的
David, we can't risk it. You know we can't.
我会把他脑袋崩开花  12  13
I will blow his fucking head off. 12, 13,
- 14  - 快换个位置
- 14... - Fucking shift then.
15  16
...15, 16...
大卫  我命令你离开
David, I'm ordering you to go.
17  18  19  20
...17, 18, 19, 20...
- 钥匙  钥匙在谁那儿呢  - 21
- Keys. Who's got the fucking keys?! - ...21,
22  23  24
22, 23, 24,
- 25  26  - 就这样  继续动
- 25, 26... - That's it, keep going.
- 让我能开枪  - 27  28  29  30
- Give me a clear shot. - ...27, 28, 29, 30,
- 31  32  - 克里斯  他走了
- 31, 32. - Chris, he's going.
- 他走了  - 很好
- He's gone. - Good.
如果我能打通电话  就没人会受伤
No one gets hurt if I get my call.
别再打这个号码了
Don't call this number again.
- 别乱动了  - 抱歉  我抽筋了
- Stop shifting about. - Sorry, I've got cramp.
混蛋
Fucker.
我收到英国警方的消息
I'm hearing from the British cops
他没和谈判专家交涉成功
he's failed to engage with their negotiator.
科鲁兹探员  你能让我们商量下吗
Agent Cruz, could you give us a moment please?
当然
Sure. Yep.
我们必须告诉比利发生了什么
We have to tell Billy what's happening.
比利不在  好吗
Billy's not here, okay?
我不能就这样给他打电话
I can't just call him up.
他在哪
Where is he?
他在进行十天的静默修行  现在第六天
He's six days into a ten-day silent retreat.
- 静默修行  - 就他自己
- A silent retreat? - Just him alone,
不跟任何人讲话  与世隔绝
not speaking to anyone, total isolation.
他周末时不时做过排毒  但这可是十天
He's done tech detox weekends here and there, but ten days.
我很不想掺和这事
And I'm very reluctant to step into that.
但你知道他在哪吧
But you do know where he is, right?
他不知道我知道  但我当然知道
Well, he doesn't know it but of course I do.
(犹他州  熔炉谷)
鲍尔先生
Mr. Bauer?
有人吗
Hello?
鲍尔先生
Mr. Bauer?
很抱歉打扰
I'm so sorry to interrupt
但有件事你得知道一下
but there's a situation you need to know about.
英国有个人把我们的一名实习生劫持了
Someone in the United kingdom has taken one of our interns hostage
还威胁要杀他
and they're threatening to kill him
除非你能跟他通电话
unless they can speak to you on the phone.
操
Oh, fuck.
他差点撞上我们
And he nearly hit us and then,
然后他就冲进那边的田地了
he just crashed into that field over there.
就在那时他们喊道  "有枪"
That's when they shouted, "Gun."
退后  女士们先生们
Stay back, ladies and gents.
(仅限紧急情况  生活碎片)
(生活碎片  输入密码)
他刚登录了  此时此刻
He just logged in. Like, right now.
他在做什么
What's he doing?
好像在看现场围观群众的推文
Looks like he's looking at posts from bystanders at the scene.
(为跟那疯子一起困在车中的人质祈祷  太可怕了)
(想想看跟一个要崩了你的人一起困在车上  可怜虫)
你多大了
How old are you?
22岁
Twenty-two.
有女友了吗
Have you got a girlfriend?
或者男友  伴侣  什么的
Or a boyfriend? Partner? Whatever?
目前没有
Not at the moment.
如果你自首  他们可能网开一面
You know, if you give yourself in, they might go easy on you.
我不能那么做
I can't do that.
这是我最后一天
This is my last day.
我想跟那个人通话
I wanna talk to the guy.
这不是个好主意
That's not a good idea.
于情于法  我强烈反对这样做
Legally and personally, I strongly advise against that.
万一他要一百万  你怎么办呢
What do you do if he asks for a million dollars?
告诉他我们给他
Tell him he can have it.
- 我们不能给钱  - 我不是说真的给他
- We cannot give money... - I'm not talking about giving him money.
我是说给我们争取时间
I'm talking about buying us some more time.
一旦提到这种交易
The moment any kind of transaction gets mentioned...
别管什么钱了  我操
Jesus, fuck the fucking money! Holy shit!
说实话  鲍尔先生
To be blunt, Mr. Bauer,
那人可能打算一跟你通上话
for all we know, this guy's planning on executing the hostage
就马上处决人质
the moment he has you on the line.
我感觉不会
I don't get that feeling.
我觉得这件事由不得感觉
I don't think we can trust feelings on this.
也许这正是问题所在
Well, maybe that's part of the problem.
我想跟他通话
I wanna talk to him.
连新闻车都派过来了
They've got a news van as well.
我妈肯定得吓坏了
My mum will be terrified.
她总是担心我  这又是...
She worries about me all the time and this is...
你妈妈完全不用担心
Your mum's got nothing to worry about.
- 她当然得担心  - 假的
- Yes, she does, she... - It's not real.
这把枪  是假的
The gun, it's not real.
- 什么  - 这是个仿制品
- What? - It's a replica.
- 该死  - 待命  待命
- Fuck! - Stand by, stand by.
不要惊动他  要让他自己泄气
We don't wanna spook him. We want him getting bored.
长官  是假的
Ma'am. It's not real.
- 什么  - 他告诉杰登说他的枪
- What? - His gun, he's just told Jaden
不是真的  是个仿制品
it's not real, it's a replica.
几位  我刚刚得知他的枪是假的
Guys, I've just been told the gun's not real.
枪是假的  我们这边也听到了
The gun's not real. We heard that at our end.
谢天谢地  谢天谢地
Oh, thank God. Thank God.
那就把他交给我们吧  失陪了
We'll deal with him now, if you'll excuse me.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 西蒙  给我防弹背心  - 是  长官
- Simon, I'll need a vest. - Ma'am?
别动  别想下车
Don't move. Don't try to get out.
我开了童锁  而且他们的枪可是真的
I've got the child lock on and they've got real guns out there.
我们要是扭打起来  都有可能被他们打死
We start struggling about, they could hit either one of us.
比利  这是枪手手机的实时信号
Billy, this is a live feed from the gunman's cell.
- 他听不见你  好吗  - 好
- He can't hear you, okay? - Okay...
- 把他的电话接过来  - 天啊  好吧
- Patch his phone through. - Jesus. Okay.
- 至少把我的手解开  - 听着  现在还不行
- At least untie my hands. - Listen, I can't do it yet.
得让他们再多相信一会儿的  好吗
Just got to make them believe it a little bit longer, all right?
直到我和鲍尔通上话
Until I speak to Bauer.
看来枪不是真的
Looks like the gun is not real.
我们刚刚听到他告诉人质枪是仿制品
We just heard him tell the hostage it's a replica.
他是想赌一把
He was spinning the wheel.
- 他说什么  - 枪是假的
- What did he say? - Well, it's not a real gun.
各单位注意  劫匪所持枪支无杀伤力
All units, weapon is a non-firing replica...
有人来了  有人来了
Someone's coming, someone's coming.
怎么回事
What the fuck...?
(热门话题  伊维尔姆)
(怎么回事  警笛大作  我哥们说 伊维尔姆附近被警察封了 现场太紧张了)
(警察听见劫匪告诉人质说枪是假的)
枪是真的  退后  退后
The gun is real! Get back! Get back!
- 枪是真的  - 视野清楚  可以击毙
- The gun is real! - Got a clear view for critical shot.
- 退后  - 克里斯  别再这么闹下去了
- Get back over there! - Chris, we need to stop this now.
只要我跟比利·鲍尔通上话我就停手
It'll stop when I speak to Billy Bauer!
- 那时才能停  - 他在美国
- Then it'll stop! - He's in America.
他们联系不到他
They can't contact him yet.
胡扯  他们肯定早就告诉他了
Fuck off. They must have told him by now.
你们在拖延时间
You're just biding time.
没人在拖延时间  我们非常当真的
No one's biding time. We're taking this all very seriously.
你不如先让杰登
Now why don't you let Jade...
允许开枪
Shot authorized.
该死  看不见了  无法击毙劫匪
Fuck! Can't see. No clear view for a critical shot.
大家立即退后寻找掩护
Everyone back behind cover, now.
你没事  没事的
You're okay. You're okay.
你们在偷听是不是  那就听好
You are listening in, so listen to this.
我只是擦伤了  还活得好好的
He only fucking clipped me. I'm still here.
如果五分钟内
If you don't phone back
比利·鲍尔不回我电话
with Billy Bauer in the next five minutes,
我就破罐破摔
it all kicks off.
我说真的  我现在要挂电话
I mean it. I am hanging up this phone
如果五分钟之内你们不回电话
and if you don't call me back within the next five minutes,
我就开枪杀人
I'm fucking doing it.
最后通牒  听到了吗  最后通牒
That's final. Okay? It's final.
枪的事我说谎了
I lied about the gun.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
- 佩内  你还在吗  - 比利  我在
- Pen? Pen, are you still there? - Bill, I'm here.
把我接过去  让我和他说话
Put me through. Put me through to this guy.
先生  你不能这么做
Sir, you... you can't do that.
不好意思  你少对我指手画脚好吗
Excuse me, please don't tell me what I can and can't do, okay?
鲍尔先生  这是勒索
Mr. Bauer, this is an extortion attempt.
佩内  把他挂了
Pen, cut him off.
- 把那联调局混蛋挂了  - 比利
- Cut Agent FBI Douchebag off. - Billy...
我强烈建议您
In the strongest possible terms,
不要与这个人谈话
I suggest you do not engage with this individual.
- 马上挂掉  - 比利  不要
- Cut him off now! - Bill, don't...
好了  佩内  把他的号码给我
All right, Pen, give me his number.
- 比利  - 有他的号码吗
- Bill. - We got his number?
他叫什么
What's his name?
克里斯托弗·吉尔海尼  把他的号码给我
Christopher Gillhaney? Give me his number.
比利  我不能给你
Bill, I'm not gonna give you that.
今天大家都吃错药了吗  我不是在请求你
Did everyone catch the same disease today? I didn't ask you.
你不能把自己卷进去
You cannot expose yourself to that.
我的笔记本在吗
My laptop in there?
- 比利  - 在
- Bill? - Yeah.
- 有卫星信号吗  - 有
- And a sat link? - Yes.
滚你们吧  我自己查
Fuck it. I'll get it myself.
- 比利  - 再见
- Bill. - Peace.
比利
Bill.
佩内洛普怎么说的来着  你能帮我记一下吗
What did Penelope say? Can you make a note for me?
克里斯托弗·迈克尔·吉尔海尼
Christopher Michael Gillhaney.
- 克里斯托弗·迈克尔·吉尔海尼  - 英国
- Christopher Michael Gillhaney. - UK,
08年注册  最近一年半未登录
user since '08, didn't log on for 18 months.
抱歉  你叫什么
Sorry, what's your name?
蒂比
Tipi.
你好  我是比利
Hi, I'm Billy.
蒂比  我这个位置唯一的好处
Tipi, really the only good thing about my position
就是我偶尔能进入
is every once in a while I get to invoke...
上帝模式
God-mode.
克里斯托弗  是克里斯托弗吗  喂
Christopher? Is that Christopher? Hello?
是  我在
Yeah, I'm here.
是我
It's me.
我是比利·鲍尔
I'm Billy Bauer.
- 你有话想对我说  - 没错  是
- You wanted to talk to me? - I did. I did, yeah. I do.
那好  你跟我说上话了
Okay, well, uh... you got me on the line.
这么着吧  不如你先
Tell you what, why don't you let
放了我们的杰登
our guy Jaden there go and, uh...
我们俩可以  聊聊
you and I can just, you know, chat?
我们可以聊聊
We can talk about...
你想要的东西
whatever it is you want.
如果我放了他  你会挂电话的
If I let him go, you'll hang up.
我不会挂电话的  克里斯托弗
I'm not gonna hang up, Christopher.
- 我要你听我说  - 我在听
- I want you to listen to me! - I'm listening.
先不要...炸毛  好吗
Let's just not... blow up, okay?
我们  冷静点
Let's just, you know, be calm
你就告诉我  你到底要什么
and you'll just kind of tell me what it is that you want.
我刚和你说了  我要你听我说
I just told you. I want you to listen to me.
- 好好听我说  - 我在听
- Just fucking listen to me. - I'm listening.
这里没有其他人
There's no one else here.
好吗  克里斯  只有你和我
Okay, Chris? It's just... it's you and me.
我在仔细听
You have my attention.
- 克里斯  - 嗯  我只是...
- Chris? - Yeah, I'm just...
我只是...有点难理清楚我的思路
I'm just... it's hard to get my thoughts in order.
我已经演练过了  我...
I've rehearsed this though, and I just...
没关系  慢慢来  你...
That's okay. Take your time, man. Just...
慢慢来
Take your time.
你运作生活碎片
You run Smithereen.
从2008年起
Since 2008.
我以前总用生活碎片
I used to use Smithereen all the time.
- 好吧  - 一刻不停那种
- Okay. - I mean, constantly.
我的手机简直是黏在我手上
Like, my phone was glued to my hand.
我就是那种典型的网瘾
I was the whole cliché, you know,
早上睁眼就看手机  晚上睡前也在看手机
first thing I saw in the morning, last thing I saw at night.
塔姆辛...
Tamsin was...
克里斯  我在呢
Chris? I'm here.
塔姆辛也一样  她是我未婚妻
Tamsin was the same. She was my fiancée.
三年前
Three years ago...
我和她一起开车回家
I was driving home with her.
我们去看了我妈妈
We'd been visiting my mum.
我妈妈病了  我们去看了她
My mum was sick and we'd been visiting my mum
我当时正开车载着塔姆辛回我们家
and I was driving Tamsin back to our flat.
她当时睡着了
She was asleep.
她累了  我就开车带她回家
She was tired and I'm just driving her home.
路上很无聊
And it was boring.
我无聊了
I got bored.
我当时可能每过十秒就会觉得无聊吧
I got bored every ten seconds back then, I think,
我在一条路上
and I'm on this A road.
四周非常安静  道路笔直
It was very quiet, straight...
我的手机突然亮了  我就打开看
...and my phone lights up and I check it.
我就看了一眼
I just glanced at it, you know.
只是一条通知
There's this little notification thing
有人赞了
saying someone liked a comment
我对他们照片的评论
that I made about some photo of theirs.
我就看了一眼
I just glanced at it, you know.
就那么短短的一瞬
That's all the time it took.
她挣扎了两个月才死去
It took her two months to die.
我一直陪在她床边  没有用
I was at her bedside. It was no use.
另一辆车里的那个男人也死了
The man in the other car died, too.
他喝醉了  他全责  他们说都是他的错
He was drunk. He got the blame. They said it was him.
所有人都很同情我  不幸先生
Everyone felt sorry for me. Mr. Tragic.
连她父母也这么觉得
Even her parents.
在她的葬礼上  她母亲还安慰我
At her funeral, you know, her mum was comforting me.
她母亲
Her fucking mum.
我该怎么和她说
What could I say to her?
没有人想知道自己女儿的死
Nobody wants to hear that their daughter's dead
是因为我在看手机
because I was looking at me fucking phone.
后来  所有人都让我去接受悲伤疏导
Afterwards, everyone tried to get me to go to grief counseling.
- 是佩内  - 要我好好谈谈
- It's Pen. - Talk about it.
说出...我的感受
Just say... say how you feel.
(心理团队筹划了跟克里斯谈话的策略)
可我...
And I'm thinking...
我什么都说不出来
I can't say a fucking thing.
(建议)
因为我的感受就是  是我杀了她
Because how I feel is that I fucking killed her.
是我杀了她
I killed her.
是我
Me.
我为一张狗的照片...杀了她
I killed her over a fucking... dog photo.
我就为那个害死了她
I killed her over that.
(1.让他知道你在听)
我明白
I hear you.
什么
What?
我说
I said...
"我明白 在听"
"I hear you."
你当然在听我说话
Of course you fucking hear me.
(2.站在他的角度共情)
你听起来很痛苦
You sound like you're in a lot of pain.
上帝啊  说点人话吧
Oh, Jesus fucking Christ! Speak like a fucking human being!
你说你在听  那你就好好听
You said you hear me so fucking hear me.
对不起  对不起
I'm sorry. Okay? I'm sorry.
他们给了我一些扯淡的建议
They gave me bullshit advice.
- 什么谈话要点  - 谈话要点
- Fucking talking points. - Talking points.
- 该死的  - 我知道
- Fucking hell. - I know.
该死  我...
Fuck! I'm...
我不知道该怎么和你说
I don't know what to say to you.
好吗
Okay?
这是事实
That's the truth.
我不知道该说什么  我不知道你想让我说什么
I don't know what to say. I don't know what you want me to say.
我知道是我
I know it was me.
是我  开车的是我  是我的错
It was me. I was driving. It was my fault.
我从来没有和任何人说过  因为那有什么用
I never told anyone before because what good would that do,
或者我可以写下来
or I could write it all down
留遗言  自尽
and leave a... A note, shoot myself,
但那又有什么用
but what good would that do?
但我想我能告诉你
But I thought I could tell you.
如果我能让你听我说
If I could get you to listen.
那是你的东西  你创建的
It was your thing, you built it.
我听说你是故意开发成那样的
I heard that that you make these things that way.
令人上瘾
Addictive.
让人根本移不开目光
So that you can't take your eyes off them.
好样的
Well, job done.
算是我的用户反馈了
Bit of user feedback for you there.
在下一次更新时考虑进去吧
Maybe factor that into your next update.
你未婚妻的事我很抱歉
I'm so sorry about your girl.
真的  我
Truly. I'm, uh...
本来不该是这样的
It wasn't supposed to be like this.
我们的整个平台  我对天发誓
Our whole platform, I swear to God.
我创建的时候是一回事
It was... like, it was one thing when I started it
后来就  我不知道
and then it just... I don't know,
后来就变成了另一回事
it just became this whole other fucking thing.
是逐渐改变的  他们说
I mean, it got there by degrees, you know, they said...
"比利  你必须不断优化
"Bill, you gotta keep optimizing,
抓住人们的注意力"
you gotta keep people engaged."
直到它变得更像一根吸毒管
Until it was more like a crack pipe.
就像拉斯维加斯赌场
It was like some kind of fucking Vegas casino where...
而且我们把所有的门都焊死了
And we'd sealed off all the fucking doors.
他们有一个部门
They've got a department...
他们的工作就是故意调整成这样
All they do is tweak it like that on purpose.
他们专攻你的多巴胺
They've got dopamine targets
而我什么也阻止不了
and there's nothing I can do to stop it.
是我创建的  可我什么也阻止不了
I started it. There's nothing I can do to fucking stop it.
我现在就像是  扯淡的幌子
I'm like some kind of... fucking bullshit front-man now.
我对天发誓  我来这里静修
I swear to God, I've been on this retreat,
本应该是十天的
supposed to be for ten days...
结果才过了两天
After, like, day two,
我就决定  去它的
I decided, fuck it.
我退出生活碎片  到此为止  我不干了
I quit Smithereen. That's it, I'm out.
闭嘴
Hey. Shut up!
- 我绝不...  - 闭嘴
- No way I'm... - Shut up.
我才不在乎你现在做什么
I don't give a fuck what you do now.
自暴自弃  或者庆祝胜利  我不在乎
Beat yourself up or fucking run a victory lap, I don't care.
我只是想把我的想法说出来
I just wanted to say my piece.
我要挂了
I'm gonna go now.
克里斯
Chris...
你会放了我们的人吗
you gonna let our guy go?
- 当然会  - 谢天谢地
- Of course I am. - Oh, thank God.
我会的  我本就是这么打算的
I'm going to. I always was, all along.
现在我要离开了
And now I'm out of here.
等等  克里斯  离开
Wait, Chris, um, out of here
- 意思是...  - 意思是离开这个世界
- as in... - As in out of here.
- 不然你以为是什么意思  - 不
- What do you think I fucking mean? - No.
不  什么  别
No, what? Don't...
你不必那么做
You don't have to do that.
克里斯  你不非得那么做
Chris, you do not have to do that.
我不能活下去  我害死了她
I can't stay here, not after what I did to her.
- 我必须死  - 不  你什么都不必做
- I have to. - No, you don't have to do anything!
你不必浪费你的生命
You don't have to waste your life.
已经浪费了
It is wasted.
如果有什么我能做的  克里斯
If there's anything that I can do, Chris,
你得给我个机会  好吗
you gotta give me a shot here, okay?
一定有什么我能做的
There's gotta be something that I can do,
哪怕是一件小事
even if it's something small.
一定有一件我能帮你做的小事
There's gotta be one small thing that I can do for you.
求你了  克里斯
Please, Chris, just...
克里斯  任何事
Chris, anything.
你认识人际圈的老板吗
Do you know the guy who owns Persona?
认识  我认识柯蒂斯
Yeah, I know Curtis. Sure.
- 你好  - 是海莉·布莱克伍德吗
- Hello? - Hayley Blackwood?
是我
Speaking.
这里是旧金山的人际圈总部
I'm calling from Persona in San Francisco.
有人让我把一些信息告诉你
I've been asked to pass on some information to you.
是吗
You have?
他和他谈过了
He's spoken to him.
我现在放你走了  杰登  好吗
I'm gonna let you go now, Jaden. Okay?
谢谢
Thanks.
你可以起来了
You can get up.
小心  小心  动作别太突然
Careful, careful. No sudden movements now.
我们不想吓到他们  好吗
We don't wanna spook them, okay?
把手腕伸出来
Hold out your wrists.
他要放了他
He's cutting him free.
抱歉让你经历这一切
I'm sorry for putting you through all of this.
没关系
It's okay.
快点  快点  还磨蹭什么...
Come on, come on, what's taking...
别自杀  伙计
Don't kill yourself, man.
说真的  我舅舅自杀了
Seriously, my uncle killed hisself
把我们全家都毁了
and it fucked my whole family up.
我妈妈现在还很难过  我现在就出去
My mum's still a mess. I'll go out there right now
然后我会告诉他们所有人
and then I'll tell all of them,
我会告诉他们你没伤害我
I'll tell them that you didn't hurt me.
你人真好  你太善良了
That's very good of you. That's very kind of you.
但我不想再活下去了
But I don't wanna be here anymore.
我等你走远了再动手
I won't do it until you're away from the car.
说真的  克里斯  你不想这么做的
Seriously, Chris, you don't wanna do this...
我知道你是好心
I know you mean well,
但是求你了  求你下车吧
but, please, just please get out of the car.
求你了
Please.
我下不了车  你没解除童锁
I can't get out the car, you left the child lock on.
不不不  拜托  不要
Oh, no, no, no. Please, don't.
- 别管我了  - 你不必这么做
- Just leave me to it. - You don't have to do this!
他们在挣扎  你能瞄准吗
They're struggling. Have you got a clear shot?
能
Affirmative.
允许射击
Shot authorized.
操
Fuck.
- 把枪放下  伙计  - 不
- Just drop it, man! - No.
没有命中
Target missed.
允许射击
Authorized.